<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>matt &#8211; Six Degrees of Procrastination</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/matt/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 20:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.0.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Day 11 Turkey &#8211; Istanbul</title>
		<link>/day-11-turkey-istanbul/</link>
		<comments>/day-11-turkey-istanbul/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 10:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=622</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After waking up from a short nights sleep next to some road works, we decided to venture back into the outskirts of Istanbul in order to find some good camping spots for our trip across Turkey. Due to the shear &#8230; <a href="/day-11-turkey-istanbul/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After waking up from a short nights sleep next to some road works, we decided to venture back into the outskirts of Istanbul in order to find some good camping spots for our trip across Turkey. Due to the shear amount of sweat each team member is producing, a shower is high up on the agenda. We pulled up in a suburb of Istanbul, looking at the city on Google does not do justice to how HUGE it really is, and started to venture out.</p>
<p>Our arch-nemesis the British weather, had finally caught us up after trying to escape it with some long driving days and as soon as we left the ambulances it started to pour down. It appears to be an unusual thing in Turkey as the shop keepers all came out to look. Our deepest apologies to Istanbul for bringing the English rain. However, the shopping centre we took refuge in turned out to fantastic, with everyone being very friendly with us. We managed to have brunch with water, bread and a vast selection of Turkish food for just 10 lera (£3) each. Thoroughly stuffed we went for a stroll about town and found a fitness park and up a hill another great view of Istanbul. The heat got the better of us and we retreated back to the shopping mall for air conditioning and internet.</p>
<p>We have now found some good camping spots for our trip across Turkey and if the people in the capital are this nice, we can&#8217;t wait to meet the local people further out. We don&#8217;t know the next time we will have good internet, so cannot say for sure when blog posts will be posted as we are now officially in ASIA!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Day_11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-633" title="Day_11" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Day_11-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Day_11-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Day_11-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/day-11-turkey-istanbul/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 9 Romania &#8211; Transfagarasan &#038; The Beach!</title>
		<link>/day-9-romania-transfagarasan-the-beach/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 10:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=610</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Starting from our wild camp, we drove towards Fagaras in the hope to find the Transfagarasan mountain road. We had heard it had only recently re-opened and many of us were looking forward to the spectacular views that we had &#8230; <a href="/day-9-romania-transfagarasan-the-beach/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090531.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-607" title="Transfagarasen" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090531-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090531-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090531-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>Starting from our wild camp, we drove towards Fagaras in the hope to find the Transfagarasan mountain road. We had heard it had only recently re-opened and many of us were looking forward to the spectacular views that we had heard so much about. On the climbing of the hill, it was found quickly that Adventure was developing an overheating problem. A quick pitstop in a layby and the engine fan was rewired to a switch, allowing the fan to be switched on at will.</p>
<p>Further up, the road that was already stunning only improved. With the trees surrounding the road on the way up, the views were tantalising as we could only see glimpses. Then, the road opened up for the final ascent with amazing driving and spectacular views. The ambulances themselves tried to prove their handling capability on these winding roads, with Endeavour struggling with the vibrations but this could not detract from the epic setting. We then continued up to the top of a rather sketchy peice of road. On reaching the top we were surprised to find most of Romania is seemed sitting with tables and chairs having the lunch and realised just how much of a perfect setting this would be to wild camp &#8211; if only we had found it the night before!</p>
<p>We decided to move through the tunnel and away from the tourists to stop for even more amazing views before the 1800km decent. The destination was the town of Constanta on the Black sea. To get to Constanta we intentionally avoided Bucharest to make sure we did not get stuck in traffic. The ring road looked the best option although it turned the surface had yet to be laid. On reaching the motorway that took us away everyone was feeling a lot more comfortable. With a false sense of security we drove down the very smooth motorway until Alex spotted a boulder about the size of a beachball lying in the middle of the lane. Both A&amp;E managed to swerve to avoid and continued to Constanta more gingerly. We drove east until we hit the Black sea, before continuing north to find a beach. With it being the perfect camping site, we had a dip in the sea before a chilled out evening in the sun. Pretty crazy roadtrip just for the beach!</p>
<div id="attachment_617" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P7151466.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-617" title="grerry" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P7151466-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P7151466-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P7151466-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P7151466.jpg 1365w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Greg and Berry enjoy the cool Black Sea waters</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 8 Hungary to Romania</title>
		<link>/day-8-hungary-to-romania/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 09:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Awaking quite a lot later than usual and with sore heads for most of the team. Nethertheless we set out with the intention of reaching the beginning of the famous Transfagarasan Highway, a road across the Fagarasan mountain range in &#8230; <a href="/day-8-hungary-to-romania/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Awaking quite a lot later than usual and with sore heads for most of the team. Nethertheless we set out with the intention of reaching the beginning of the famous Transfagarasan Highway, a road across the Fagarasan mountain range in the centre of Romania. As we journied further south towards Romania, the clouds that had been following us disappeared and the baking hot sun appeared. This was initially pleasant until the temperature climbed to 38C and the sweating began&#8230;</p>
<p>Today turned out to contain some of the most fantastic scenery of the trip so far, with views across the flat farmland interspersed with forested peaks. We settled down to camp in a small pebbled country lane in the shadow of the mountains with nothing but millions of flies to keep us company.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090264.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-604" title="rom_sunset" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090264-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090264-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090264-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/P1090264.jpg 1365w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 7 &#8211; Slovakia &#8211; Hungary</title>
		<link>/day-7-slovakia-hungary/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 09:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=597</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After waking up slightly later than planned again, we soon realised we had camped right next to a climbing area. A quick pack up and shop at Tesco meant we were well prepared on our way for a short day. &#8230; <a href="/day-7-slovakia-hungary/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After waking up slightly later than planned again, we soon realised we had camped right next to a climbing area. A quick pack up and shop at Tesco meant we were well prepared on our way for a short day. Two issues have been niggling us on the road for a while: only having one spare tyre; and more importantly the vibration in Endeavour between 50 and 60 mph. Since we will soon be out of the EU we decided to sort these problems today.</p>
<p>A quick drive into Budapest and we found possibly the best Opel garage in the world. The gentleman that ran it spoke great English and had no problem giving us 4 tyres from the pile of used ones they had at the back of the garage. After trying to fix our spare wheel he then sourced a spare for us and we had the tyres swapped to this. Unfortunately no amount of his mechanics head scratching and arm folding managed to fix Endevour’s shaking problem. They concluded the gearbox was on its way out. Bravely we have decided to plow on and just drive carefully&#8230;.!</p>
<p>We quickly found a campsite in the centre of Budapest and everyone had a well earned shower and another pasta and sauce dinner. There turned out to be a number of fellow travellers in the campsite, and we met a couple who have been on the road for nine months already! After dinner we headed into town to find out what Budapest had to offer. Soon after venturing towards the centre of town we found what is reported to be “The Best Bar in the World” (according to the Lonely Planet guide) and with cheap beer, live music and friendly punters we were inclined to agree. What followed was an awesome night and a painful hangover&#8230;.</p>
<div id="attachment_602" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/20120713_222855.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-602" title="best_bar" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/20120713_222855-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/20120713_222855-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/20120713_222855-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/20120713_222855.jpg 1365w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Best Bar in the World is in Budapest!</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All Signed Up!</title>
		<link>/all-signed-up/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 13:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=466</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After the horrible and painful removing of the old signs we are incredibly pleased to show everyone our fantastic new signs courtesy of GRS Signs. I think you will agree the improvement of the vehicle&#8217;s appearance is phenomenal! We would like &#8230; <a href="/all-signed-up/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the horrible and painful removing of the old signs we are incredibly pleased to show everyone our fantastic new signs courtesy of <a href="http://www.grs-signs.com/">GRS Signs</a>. I think you will agree the improvement of the vehicle&#8217;s appearance is phenomenal!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/243792_3323670418472_430956160_o.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-481" title="243792_3323670418472_430956160_o" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/243792_3323670418472_430956160_o-1024x764.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="477" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/243792_3323670418472_430956160_o-1024x764.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/243792_3323670418472_430956160_o-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/243792_3323670418472_430956160_o.jpg 1296w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>We would like to thank GRS for their fantastic help and work towards these signs! We would also like to thank everyone who has sponsored us recently, we couldn&#8217;t possibly get these vehicles to where they are needed without you!</p>
<p>Finally we would like to present A&amp;E &#8211; Adventure &amp; Endeavour, our two ambulances, along with most of the team!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/468862_3324469478448_1357718530_o.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-483" title="468862_3324469478448_1357718530_o" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/468862_3324469478448_1357718530_o-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/468862_3324469478448_1357718530_o-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/468862_3324469478448_1357718530_o-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stripping The Ambulances</title>
		<link>/stripping-the-ambulances/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 21:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=464</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the past 5 days the team has been busy stripping the old signs off the ambulances. This turned out to be a mammoth task and took well over 40 hours to do! It turns out removing 8 year old stickers without removing vehicle &#8230; <a href="/stripping-the-ambulances/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/strip_ambulance.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-477 aligncenter" title="strip_ambulance" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/strip_ambulance-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/strip_ambulance-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/strip_ambulance-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/strip_ambulance.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></p>
<p>For the past 5 days the team has been busy stripping the old signs off the ambulances. This turned out to be a mammoth task and took well over 40 hours to do! It turns out removing 8 year old stickers without removing vehicle paint is a painstaking process. This was not helped by only owning one tool to do the job, a butter knife ( which Berry swears is a family heirloom &#8230;&#8230;ooops).</p>
<p>The reason for removing the old signs is to make way for the brand new ones which will give the vehicles a more ambulance-y look as well as adorning our sponsors!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/stripped_ambulance.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-478" title="stripped_ambulance" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/stripped_ambulance-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/stripped_ambulance-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/stripped_ambulance-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/stripped_ambulance.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Team Kit Delivery</title>
		<link>/team-kit-delivery/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 15:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=469</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today we took delivery of the team clothing! T-shirts and Hoodies with the team logo across the front and website across the back. We now look even more prepared than we are feeling! Many thanks to Signature Leisurewear for helping us sort &#8230; <a href="/team-kit-delivery/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we took delivery of the team clothing! T-shirts and Hoodies with the team logo across the front and website across the back. We now look even more prepared than we are feeling! Many thanks to <a href="http://www.signatureleisurewear.co.uk/">Signature Leisurewear</a> for helping us sort out these garments!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/clothingsdop.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-475" title="clothingsdop" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/clothingsdop-1024x764.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="477" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/clothingsdop-1024x764.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/clothingsdop-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/clothingsdop.jpg 1296w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Real-time Journey Tracking</title>
		<link>/real-time-journey-tracking/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 01:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=437</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce that we have purchased a SPOT Messenger! The SPOT Messenger is a GPS device which is able to transmit its location via satellite back to the UK and onto the internet. One of the SPOT &#8230; <a href="/real-time-journey-tracking/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that we have purchased a SPOT Messenger! The SPOT Messenger is a GPS device which is able to transmit its location via satellite back to the UK and onto the internet. One of the SPOT Messenger&#8217;s features is tracking, which reports the location of the device every 10minutes back to the UK.</p>
<p>Having so many Engineers in the team, we have managed to get the location reports to appear on the website at <a title="Realtime Location" href="/realtime-location/">Real-Time Location</a>. This will allow you to watch our journey progress in real-time as it unfolds and see exactly where we are! As well as Tracking, the device also provides S.O.S Beaconing for emergencies and other features used to keep people updated.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" title="SPOT Messenger" src="http://www.findmespot.com/images/spot2_prodpage.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="239" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">On Sunday, Berry, Matt and Alex will be cycling the 54 Miles from London to Brighton for the British Heart Foundation. They will be testing the Tracking system for the day so if you fancy watching their progress be sure to look any time after <strong>8:00 am 17th June</strong>  at <strong><a title="Realtime Location" href="/realtime-location/">Real-Time Location</a> </strong>!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Faith, Hope and Charity</title>
		<link>/faith-hope-and-charity/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 09:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=400</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last Friday, 8th June, four members of the SDOP team (Berry, Ian, Rich and Neil) went over to the Isle of Wight to receive a fantastic donation from the Faith, Hope and Charity charity shop based in Totland. Faith, Hope &#8230; <a href="/faith-hope-and-charity/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday, 8th June, four members of the SDOP team (Berry, Ian, Rich and Neil) went over to the Isle of Wight to receive a fantastic donation from the Faith, Hope and Charity charity shop based in Totland. Faith, Hope and Charity donates to many charitable causes and we feel very honoured that they would help us with our journey!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/shrunk_website.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-401" title="Faith Hope and Charity" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/shrunk_website-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/shrunk_website-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/shrunk_website-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>To see more photos of the team receiving this awesome donation (monetary and dimensions of cheque) head over to the gallery!</p>
<p>P.S I also hear the cycle over to the Isle of Wight was a pretty intense battle with the wind. Pedalling to be able go down hill sounds like an interesting experience!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visa Return!</title>
		<link>/visa-return/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 13:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[matt]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The distinct lack of blog posts in the last two weeks has been caused by the whole team being busy with exams and courseworks. However the entire team are now enjoying the freedom of being Graduands (Except 3rd Year Alex). &#8230; <a href="/visa-return/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The distinct lack of blog posts in the last two weeks has been caused by the whole team being busy with exams and courseworks. However the entire team are now enjoying the freedom of being Graduands (Except 3rd Year Alex). Thankfully this means we can get on with really sorting out all the equipment left to buy and kitting up the Ambulances!</p>
<p>Today, after a nail biting five week wait, we received our passports back from Real Russia. They now contain 5 Visas, without the Turkmenistan visa that we will get after the ferry crossing, that we will need for our journey!</p>
<p>We would like to thank &#8216;Real Russia&#8217; for being so helpful and professional with sorting out all of our Visas for us. If anyone is looking for a company to help get Visas for Russia or any other Asian country, we highly recommend them!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.realrussia.co.uk/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-390" title="real russia" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/real-russia.gif" alt="" width="177" height="68" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
